# Philipp Shergalis

# Java Software Engineer

Serbia

phillippko@gmail.com +381-61-245-1913 t.me/phillippko linkedin.com/in/phillippko

## **Summary**

Over 3 years of professional software development experience, emphasizing best practices such as code reviews, testing, documentation, automation, and coding standards. Led a victorious 5-member team in 2 student hackathons at Moscow HSE University. Created algorithmic tasks for 5 Yandex internship screening contests. Mentored 2 teams at Yandex Backend School. Proficient in diverse IT domains through self-driven learning and a solid university education.

#### **Skills**

Java, Kotlin, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Junit, Mockito, Postgres, SQL, Git, TeamCity, reliability and scaling, Liquibase, REST, gRPC, Oracle, MongoDB, Kubernetes, Terraform, Golang, Linux, JavaScript, Python.

## **Experience**

## Golang Software Engineer

Yandex, Hybrid

Decoupling Nebius. Cloud from Yandex infrastructure.

- Analyzed system usage patterns and identified redundant functionalities, resulting in accelerated decoupling processes and saving an estimated 2 months of development.
- Single-handedly migrated alerting calls to an external telephony service. This functionality is mission critical and serves more than 2000 alerting calls per month.
- Streamlined a process of onboarding by creating a comprehensive documentation recognized for its significant impact on adaptation, leading to 3 out of 5 bootcamp members to stay in the team.

#### Java/Kotlin Software Engineer

06.2021 - 04.2023 (1 year 10 months)

04.2023 - 11.2023 (8 months)

Yandex, Hybrid

- Diagnosed and resolved billing transaction issues, optimizing billion-dollars transaction flows for tax benefits and merchant debt collection, resulting in multimillion-dollar gains.
- Created abstractions, saving weeks of development time, streamlining the addition of new billings and data imports.
- Reduced the logistics billing database size by 90% through billing logic redesign and the removal of extraneous data.
- Successfully recruited and onboarded 3 aspiring developers.
- Created tasks for 5 internship screening contests and mentored 2 teams at Yandex Backend School, contributing to company branding.

# Full stack Kotlin Developer

10.2020 - 06.2021 (9 months)

Versality, Remote

- Single-handedly maintained a full-stack website using Kotlin and AngularJS.
- Leveraged technologies including Spring, Git, Docker, and PostgreSQL to implement various features.
- Delivered features such as an admin interface, promo catalogue, and notification system, enhancing the user experience.

### Education

Saint-Petersburg Polytechnic University Bachelor's degree in computer science.

2019 - 2024